<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insights on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insights on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Agile Practices for Data-driven Projects</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/fundamental-agile-practices-for-data-driven-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/fundamental-agile-practices-for-data-driven-projects/</guid>
      <description>Companies willing to move towards data-driven management should start to think about improving their agility, which means having a good understanding of what an Agile framework is about and choosing which Agile practices and methodologies are best suited to be implemented in their data projects.
Indeed, one major stumbling block for the adoption of an Agile framework in data-driven projects is the sometimes ill-informed choice of suitable tools and techniques that are valuable to teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Leadership that Business Transformation Demands</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Business transformation is best managed when there are smart leaders who recognize the needs of the organization and are willing to guide it on the right direction. The other side of the coin is that smart leadership is a critical capability that companies urgently need to equip themselves with to address all the transformational changes required to build a new culture based on agile and continuous transformation.
What&amp;rsquo;s more, smart leadership is a critical competency needed to successfully embrace Big data and AI-based advanced technology initiatives across the organization and truly reap the benefits of business transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Rules of Smartness with BDAI as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/breaking-the-rules-of-smartness-with-bdai-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/breaking-the-rules-of-smartness-with-bdai-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The combination of Big Data, analytics, and AI (BDAI) is going to generate great business opportunities and competitive advantages for companies around the world.Through the integration and interoperability of these technologies, companies are going to be able to transform their operations and business model and, in the medium and long term, obtain significant gains in efficiency and productivity.
It can be expected that the inclusion of BDAI in the culture of people will better prepare organizations to open new markets and explore (and exploit) new niches in existing markets, will allow the creation of new value offerings focused on the experiential component and personalization, and, ultimately, will contribute significantly to boosting growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Ethics as a Driver of Business Transformation</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-value-of-ethics-as-a-driver-of-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-value-of-ethics-as-a-driver-of-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Ethical considerations arising from business transformation often go unnoticed by transformational leaders, and even more so by the ICT industry and other key stakeholders who should pay attention to this key driver of transformation.
However, ethical behavior in business transformation, as in other complex decision-making environments, plays a fundamental role in achieving the expected results and establishing solid foundations on which to build a robust and smooth transformation.
Through proper examination of the ethical considerations that arise from transformation, transformational leaders can gain new perspectives to understand both the transformation processes themselves and the new organizational and societal impacts that are emerging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Systems - Boosting Your Business Smart Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/cognitive-systems-boosting-your-business-smart-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/cognitive-systems-boosting-your-business-smart-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive computing technologies are fundamentally different from all other forms of computing seen so far. They aim to continually learn from the interaction between data (structured and unstructured), context, and people, to improve learning and reasoning capabilities over time.
Similar to how human learning evolves from birth to adulthood, a cognitive system learns and becomes more intelligent over time from the information it gains each time it interacts with its environment and the experience it accumulates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Applications Worth Considering and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>The idea of quantum computing arose from the reflection made by scientists about the fundamental limits of computing. What they surmised is that if technology continued to comply with Moore’s Law (which states that the number of transistors in a microprocessor doubles approximately every 2 years), then the shrinking size of the circuits within a silicon chip would eventually reach a point where individual elements would not exceed the size of a few atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Smart organizations are constantly changing, adapting their structures, resources, and objectives as they evolve to overcome the inertia that impedes change. Building a transformation strategy on top of the dynamic capabilities and ambidexterity of the organization, and through the implementation of multiple simultaneous projects is an effective way to reduce risks and have better cost performance.
This approach when setting the business transformation strategy is different when organizations perceive the need to transform as a result of episodic external events (aka, disruptions) that alter a previous equilibrium situation and that affect the organization&amp;rsquo;s internal structures, forcing them to be replaced by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Ambidexterity, Crucial for Organizational Transformation</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-art-of-ambidexterity-crucial-for-organizational-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-art-of-ambidexterity-crucial-for-organizational-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Addressing business transformation involves developing capabilities to quickly adapt to predictable and unpredictable environmental changes and create and capture new value. Events such as the appearance of new technologies and disruptive/innovative business models, the shortening of product life cycles, and a more dynamic competitive landscape require new strategic responses from business organizations.
Those organizations that take a step forward and commit themselves to deep business transformation do so by adopting different combinations of information technologies, processes, and resources that end up impacting the entire organization and leading to profound changes in its structure, culture, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Smart Transformation by Developing Dynamic Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/tackling-smart-transformation-by-developing-dynamic-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/tackling-smart-transformation-by-developing-dynamic-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>In the new era of data and smart technologies, the consumer is king when companies must decide on new technologies and business transformation. In these new times, the tangible resources (including the tangible products) on which the fundamental competitive capabilities of businesses were based are beginning to lose relevance in favor of the intangible assets and services delivered by the organization. Furthermore, the ability of organizations to open up to the outside world and interact with other players in multiple business ecosystems becomes critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation, Evolutionary or Disruptive?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</guid>
      <description>The idea of &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo; refers to a process of profound and evolutionary change that affects all aspects of an organization, led by digital capabilities and technologies aimed at creating value. The fact that digital transformation is an evolutionary process indicates that the phenomenon of transformation is continuous; that is, it is maintained over time.
Some authors, however, argue that digital transformation involves more radical or disruptive change than simply an evolutionary process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Confused with Digitization, Digitalization and Digital Transformation?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/still-confused-with-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/still-confused-with-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Being clear about the main concepts surrounding that of digitalization is no longer straightforward. The term has been so abused by so many people with so many different intentions that it has ceased to be useful for sharing ideas with each other, and shrouded in tons of dust and without substance.
To make matters worse, the literature on digitalization and related disciplines does not help at all if we seek to clarify things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is and What Is Not Big Data?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/what-is-and-what-is-not-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/what-is-and-what-is-not-big-data/</guid>
      <description>It is not easy to define what Big Data is, or to draw a clear dividing line between what is “big” and “small” data. This difficulty is reflected in the number and variety of conceptualizations that can be found about Big Data in the literature.
Big Data promises exciting new opportunities, including unlocking new insights that can accelerate the creation of new products and services, boost customer relationships, improve operational processes, and even embrace innovative business models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Types of AI Are There and What Are They For?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-many-types-of-ai-are-there-and-what-are-they-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-many-types-of-ai-are-there-and-what-are-they-for/</guid>
      <description>The term artificial intelligence (AI) was first introduced in the 1950s as a branch of computer science concerned with the automation of intelligent behavior. Since then, AI and its associated techniques have developed rapidly to the point that today not only is there still no fully accepted definition of what AI is, but there are various approaches to it.
Most frequently, AI is associated with the ability of a machine to sense its environment, learn from experience, make decisions based on input and goals, and ultimately perform human-like tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
