<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frontiers in Business Transformation on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frontiers in Business Transformation on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Transformative Power of the Connected Autonomous Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-transformative-power-of-the-connected-autonomous-vehicle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-transformative-power-of-the-connected-autonomous-vehicle/</guid>
      <description>Connected and autonomous vehicles (CAVs) have the potential to disrupt industries and consumer behavior, transforming urban spaces, modes of transportation use, and a significant portion mobility-related employment. The arrival of CAVs on the market will generate a new world of business and social opportunities that, however, are not free from challenges and threats.
CAVs are much more than &amp;ldquo;autonomous taxis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;constructive policy dialogue&amp;rdquo;, they raise concrete questions about how to design the cities in which we will live, where businesses will be located and how consumer experiences will be designed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Big Opportunities of Big Data</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-next-big-opportunities-of-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-next-big-opportunities-of-big-data/</guid>
      <description>In the era of Big Data, great new opportunities are continually being created for virtually all business functions. Through Big Data, companies can accumulate competitive benefits, which can be conclusive if they also learn to use them on an efficient scale and are able to routinize the extraction of value from data using appropriate techniques.
In this article we examine some of the main impacts and opportunities that Big Data will continue to provide to business organizations in the development of innovative and increasingly competitive strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Key Ingredients of a Successful Cybersecurity Strategy</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-3-key-ingredients-of-a-successful-cybersecurity-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-3-key-ingredients-of-a-successful-cybersecurity-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Stories of cyber-attacks have become routine, with cyber-attackers showing increasing levels of sophistication and damage inflicted. The race to discover new ways to exploit weaknesses in the defenses of every company&amp;rsquo;s data and IT systems does not stop, so it is absolutely key that transformational leaders are aware of the magnitude of the challenges they face and understand what is at stake.
Unless transformational leaders are relentless in responding to the threats posed by cyberattacks and put all the resources necessary to mitigate them, cyberattackers will exploit the flaws and weaknesses of the organization&amp;rsquo;s data and IT systems to hijack, distort, or simply interrupt the organization&amp;rsquo;s service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-code/No-code- Unlocking Software Development Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/low-code-no-code-unlocking-software-development-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/low-code-no-code-unlocking-software-development-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Companies are facing a shortage of software developers around the world. No matter what statistic or report you read, everyone seems to agree on one thing: the number of software developers needed to cover all of the industry&amp;rsquo;s needs is staggering and only increasing.
For example, IDC has forecast a global shortage of four million software developers by 2025, while the US Bureau of Labor Statistics shows that nearly 200,000 developer jobs will be needed each year until the end of the decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Adopt Open Innovation with Agility for Business Transformation</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-to-adopt-open-innovation-with-agility-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-to-adopt-open-innovation-with-agility-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>The complex environment in which most business organizations operate around the world has made the practices that lead to open innovation become an essential tool for any transformational leader who relies on the potential of external ideas, knowledge, and technologies to create value.
Organizations with greater external knowledge and skills are in a better position to make faster decisions and adapt their operating frameworks to changes in the environment and threats from competitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Agile Practices for Transformational Leaders</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/best-agile-practices-for-transformational-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/best-agile-practices-for-transformational-leaders/</guid>
      <description>Transformational leaders committed to moving towards smart, data-driven management should start thinking about how they can improve their organization&amp;rsquo;s agility, which means first having a good understanding of what an Agile framework is about and choosing which practices and methodologies are best suited to expedite the implementation of transformation initiatives.
Not surprisingly, one of the main obstacles to adopting an Agile framework and speeding up business transformation is the often misinformed choice of the tools and techniques that are most valuable to teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Leadership that Business Transformation Demands</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Business transformation is best managed when there are smart leaders who recognize the needs of the organization and are willing to guide it on the right direction. The other side of the coin is that smart leadership is a critical capability that companies urgently need to equip themselves with to address all the transformational changes required to build a new culture based on agile and continuous transformation.
What&amp;rsquo;s more, smart leadership is a critical competency needed to successfully embrace Big data and AI-based advanced technology initiatives across the organization and truly reap the benefits of business transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Democratization of Smartness with Big Data, Analytics and AI as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-democratization-of-smartness-with-big-data-analytics-and-ai-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-democratization-of-smartness-with-big-data-analytics-and-ai-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The seamless integration of Big Data, Analytics and AI (BDAI) into solutions that meet the changing needs of business is starting to generate great business opportunities and competitive advantages for companies in all industries around the world.
Simultaneously, the rise of the &amp;ldquo;as-a-service&amp;rdquo; trend is gaining momentum thanks to the proliferation of the amount of data available and the exponential increase in computing capabilities. Not to mention that more and more companies have access to IT infrastructure and applications as a service through the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Ethics as a Driver of Business Transformation</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-value-of-ethics-as-a-driver-of-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-value-of-ethics-as-a-driver-of-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Ethical considerations arising from business transformation often go unnoticed by transformational leaders, let alone by the ICT industry and other stakeholders who should pay close attention to this key driver of transformation.
As elusive as it often seems, ethical behavior and responsibility in business transformation, as in other complex decision-making environments, play a crucial role in helping organizations achieve their business goals and establish a solid foundation on which to build a fluid transformation flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Systems - Boosting Your Business Smart Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/cognitive-systems-boosting-your-business-smart-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/cognitive-systems-boosting-your-business-smart-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive computing technologies are fundamentally different from all other forms of computing seen so far. They aim to continually learn from the interaction between data (structured and unstructured), context, and people, to improve learning and reasoning capabilities over time.
Similar to how human learning evolves from birth to adulthood, a cognitive system learns and becomes more intelligent over time from the information it gains each time it interacts with its environment and the experience it accumulates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Applications Worth Considering Today</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-today/</guid>
      <description>The idea of quantum computing emerged years ago from the reflections of a bunch of scientists about what the fundamental limits of computing were. What they assumed was that if technology continued to comply with Moore&amp;rsquo;s Law, that is, if the number of transistors in a microprocessor doubled approximately every two years, then the decreasing size of the circuits within a silicon chip would eventually reach a point where individual elements would not exceed the size of a few atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Smart organizations are constantly changing, adapting their structures, resources, and objectives as they evolve to overcome the inertia that impedes change. Building a transformation strategy on top of the dynamic capabilities and ambidexterity of the organization, and through the implementation of multiple simultaneous projects is an effective way to reduce risks and have better cost performance.
This approach when setting the business transformation strategy is different when organizations perceive the need to transform as a result of episodic external events (aka, disruptions) that alter a previous equilibrium situation and that affect the organization&amp;rsquo;s internal structures, forcing them to be replaced by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Business Transformation with Ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/managing-business-transformation-with-ambidexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/managing-business-transformation-with-ambidexterity/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s complex business context, addressing business transformation means that organizations must develop new capabilities to quickly adapt to both predictable and unpredictable environmental changes and create (and capture) new value.
External events such as the emergence of new technologies and new disruptive and innovative business models, the shortening of product life cycles and a more dynamic competitive landscape require new strategic responses.
Transformational leaders often address this challenge by adopting different combinations of information technologies, processes and resources that greatly affect the entire organization and lead to radical changes in its structure, culture, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Capabilities- The Holy Grail of Strategic Change Management</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/dynamic-capabilities-the-holy-grail-of-strategic-change-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/dynamic-capabilities-the-holy-grail-of-strategic-change-management/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s business environment marked by strong competition and continuous pressure for organizations to transform and not stop innovating, an endless number of new difficulties and challenges arise that transformational leaders must manage.
Companies need to constantly adjust their strategies to remain relevant, and having a solid business transformation strategy that is well aligned with the rest of the organization&amp;rsquo;s strategies becomes essential.
In this complicated game, it is crucial that transformational leaders effectively manage the set of capabilities that organizations possess to respond to environmental changes and maintain a high level of performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation, Evolutionary or Disruptive?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</guid>
      <description>The idea of “digital transformation” refers to a process of profound and evolutionary change that affects all aspects of an organization, led by digital capabilities and technologies aimed at creating value.
The fact that digital transformation is an evolutionary process indicates that the phenomenon of transformation is continuous; that is, it is maintained over time. However, some authors argue that digital transformation involves more radical or disruptive change than simply an evolutionary process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Confused with Digitalization vs Transformation?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/still-confused-with-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/still-confused-with-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Being clear about the key concepts involved in digital and business transformation is no longer straightforward. These terms have been so abused by so many people with so many different intentions that they have outlived their usefulness in communicating ideas and sharing a common language and are now shrouded in tons of dust and without substance.
To make matters worse, the literature on digitalization and transformarion does not help at all when transformational leaders seek to clarify things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is and What Is Not Big Data?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/what-is-and-what-is-not-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/what-is-and-what-is-not-big-data/</guid>
      <description>It is not easy to define what Big Data is, or to draw a clear dividing line between what is “big” and “small” data. This difficulty is reflected in the number and variety of conceptualizations that can be found about Big Data in the literature.
Big Data promises exciting new opportunities, including unlocking new insights that can accelerate the creation of new products and services, boost customer relationships, improve operational processes, and even embrace innovative business models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Types of AI Are There and What Are They For?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-many-types-of-ai-are-there-and-what-are-they-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-many-types-of-ai-are-there-and-what-are-they-for/</guid>
      <description>The term artificial intelligence (AI) was first introduced in the 1950s as a branch of computer science concerned with the automation of intelligent behavior. Since then, AI and its associated techniques have developed rapidly to the point that today not only is there still no fully accepted definition of what AI is, but there are various approaches to it.
Most frequently, AI is associated with the ability of a machine to sense its environment, learn from experience, make decisions based on input and goals, and ultimately perform human-like tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Insights for Transformational Leaders FrontiersInBusinessTransformation (FiBT) has been created thinking about the needs for updated and incisive knowledge that transformational leaders have to keep their organizations ahead and make them more competitive every day.
FiBT offers insights that are the result of independent research on the most relevant academic, professional and industry sources of knowledge. The research methods used include qualitative and quantitative techniques applied to data made available from relevant sources, as well as the generation of new data from participatory research processes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
