<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frontiers in Business Transformation on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frontiers in Business Transformation on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Leadership for the Future of Business Transformation</title>
      <link>/posts/a-new-leadership-for-the-future-of-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-new-leadership-for-the-future-of-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Business transformation is best managed when there are smart leaders who recognize the needs of the organization and are willing to guide it on the right direction. Smart leadership is a critical capability that companies need in order to address all the transformational changes required to build a data-driven culture in the organization. Furthermore, leadership is a critical competency to embrace Big Data throughout the organization and bring the benefits of data science to fruition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Rules of Smartness with BDAI as-a-Service</title>
      <link>/posts/breaking-the-rules-of-smartness-with-bdai-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/breaking-the-rules-of-smartness-with-bdai-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The combination of Big Data, analytics, and AI (BDAI) is going to generate great business opportunities and competitive advantages for companies around the world. Through the integration and interoperability of these technologies, companies are going to be able to transform their operations and business model and, in the medium and long term, obtain significant gains in efficiency and productivity.
It can be expected that the inclusion of BDAI in the culture of people will better prepare organizations to open new markets and explore (and exploit) new niches in existing markets, will allow the creation of new value offerings focused on the experiential component and personalization, and, ultimately, will contribute significantly to boosting growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Ethics as a Driver of Business Transformation</title>
      <link>/posts/the-value-of-ethics-as-a-driver-of-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-value-of-ethics-as-a-driver-of-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>The ethical considerations that arise from deep business transformation often go unnoticed by transformational leaders, not to say by the ICT industry. However, ethical behavior in business transformation (and in complex decision-making environments) plays an increasingly important role, since it can provide new perspectives to understand both the transformation processes themselves and the new organizational and social impacts that are emerging.
The importance of ethics will become more apparent as business transformation becomes more and more data-driven, extends to an ever-increasing number of actors, and becomes deeper and irreversible for most organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before and After Computing With Cognitive Systems</title>
      <link>/posts/the-road-ahead-for-cognitive-computing-applications-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-road-ahead-for-cognitive-computing-applications-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>The Road Ahead for Cognitive Computing Applications and Challenges Cognitive computing technologies are fundamentally different from all other forms of computing used so far. Cognitive systems continually learn from their interaction with data (structured and unstructured), contexts, and people, and thus improve their learning and reasoning capabilities over time. Similar to how human learning evolves from birth to adulthood, a cognitive system learns and becomes more intelligent over time from the information it gains each time it interacts with its environment and the experience it accumulates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Applications Worth Considering and Challenges</title>
      <link>/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>The idea of quantum computing arose from the reflection made by scientists about the fundamental limits of computing. What they surmised is that if technology continued to comply with Moore’s Law (which states that the number of transistors in a microprocessor doubles approximately every 2 years), then the shrinking size of the circuits within a silicon chip would eventually reach a point where individual elements would not exceed the size of a few atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies (I)</title>
      <link>/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-i/</guid>
      <description>Smart organizations are constantly changing, adapting their structures, resources, and objectives as they evolve to overcome the inertia that impedes change. Building a transformation strategy on top of the dynamic capabilities and ambidexterity of the company through the implementation of multiple simultaneous projects is an effective way to reduce risks and have better cost performance.
This is different from those organizations that perceive the need to transform as a result of episodic external events (or disruptions) that alter a previous equilibrium situation and that affect the internal structures of the organization, which must then be replaced by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Ambidexterity, Crucial for Organizational Transformation</title>
      <link>/posts/the-art-of-ambidexterity-crucial-for-organizational-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-art-of-ambidexterity-crucial-for-organizational-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Addressing business transformation involves developing capabilities to quickly adapt to predictable and unpredictable environmental changes and create and capture new value. Events such as the appearance of new technologies and disruptive/innovative business models, the shortening of product life cycles, and a more dynamic competitive landscape require new strategic responses from business firms.
Those organizations that take a step forward and commit themselves to deep business transformation do so by adopting different combinations of information technologies, processes, and resources that end up impacting the entire organization and leading to profound changes in its structure, culture, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Smart Transformation by Developing Dynamic Capabilities</title>
      <link>/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-ii/</guid>
      <description>In the new era of data and smart technologies, the consumer is king when firms must decide on new technologies and business transformation. In these new times, the tangible resources (including the tangible products) on which the fundamental competitive capabilities of businesses were based are beginning to lose relevance in favor of the intangible assets and services delivered by the organization. Furthermore, the ability of organizations to open up to the outside world and interact with other players in multiple business ecosystems becomes critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation, Evolutionary or Disruptive?</title>
      <link>/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</guid>
      <description>The idea of &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo; refers to a process of profound and evolutionary change that affects all aspects of an organization, led by digital capabilities and technologies aimed at creating value. The fact that digital transformation is an evolutionary process indicates that the phenomenon of transformation is continuous; that is, it is maintained over time. Some authors, however, argue that digital transformation involves more radical or disruptive change than simply an evolutionary process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Confused with the Differences between Digitization, Digitalization and Digital Transformation?</title>
      <link>/posts/still-confused-with-the-differences-between-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/still-confused-with-the-differences-between-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Being clear about the main concepts surrounding that of digitalization is no longer straightforward. The term has been so abused by so many people with so many different intentions that it has ceased to be useful for sharing ideas with each other, and shrouded in tons of dust and without substance.
To make matters worse, the literature on digitalization and related disciplines does not help at all if we seek to clarify things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Contra vagos Lorem markdownum notam si lintea meque certa en meumque illis, diu fatigant, nec praedae concustodita arcet. Paviunt castris cur errat ventis causa! Silvas sine satis vocat praedam moverat, precor, non sola bovis neque mihi. Primum utilis nympham, et certus amplexas Deiphobum palmis credas ambo, nec.
Excidit gente, si orat suo quaeque dura Calydon nata? Pars auro post stetit adfusique imis amplexus. Agmina per fabricator mittere Erymanthon habetque tot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
