<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The New Leadership that Business Transformation Demands</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Business transformation is best managed when there are smart leaders who recognize the needs of the organization and are willing to guide it on the right direction. The other side of the coin is that smart leadership is a critical capability that companies urgently need to equip themselves with to address all the transformational changes required to build a new culture based on agile and continuous transformation.
What&amp;rsquo;s more, smart leadership is a critical competency needed to successfully embrace Big data and AI-based advanced technology initiatives across the organization and truly reap the benefits of business transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Smart organizations are constantly changing, adapting their structures, resources, and objectives as they evolve to overcome the inertia that impedes change. Building a transformation strategy on top of the dynamic capabilities and ambidexterity of the organization, and through the implementation of multiple simultaneous projects is an effective way to reduce risks and have better cost performance.
This approach when setting the business transformation strategy is different when organizations perceive the need to transform as a result of episodic external events (aka, disruptions) that alter a previous equilibrium situation and that affect the organization&amp;rsquo;s internal structures, forcing them to be replaced by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Business Transformation with Ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-art-of-ambidexterity-crucial-for-organizational-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-art-of-ambidexterity-crucial-for-organizational-transformation/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s complex business context, addressing business transformation means that organizations must develop new capabilities to quickly adapt to both predictable and unpredictable environmental changes and create (and capture) new value.
External events such as the emergence of new technologies and new disruptive and innovative business models, the shortening of product life cycles and a more dynamic competitive landscape require new strategic responses.
Transformational leaders often address this challenge by adopting different combinations of information technologies, processes and resources that greatly affect the entire organization and lead to radical changes in its structure, culture, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Smart Transformation by Developing Dynamic Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/tackling-smart-transformation-by-developing-dynamic-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/tackling-smart-transformation-by-developing-dynamic-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>In the new era of data and smart technologies, the consumer is king when companies must decide on new technologies and business transformation. In these new times, the tangible resources (including the tangible products) on which the fundamental competitive capabilities of businesses were based are beginning to lose relevance in favor of the intangible assets and services delivered by the organization. Furthermore, the ability of organizations to open up to the outside world and interact with other players in multiple business ecosystems becomes critical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
