<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Explainable AI- A Gateway to Transparent Decision-Making</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/explainable-ai-a-gateway-to-transparent-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/explainable-ai-a-gateway-to-transparent-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>In the era of data-driven decision-making, businesses are increasingly turning to Artificial Intelligence (AI) to gain insights, streamline processes, and enhance competitiveness. However, as AI systems become more complex and pervasive, the need for transparency and accountability in their decision-making processes has become paramount.
This is where Explainable AI (XAI) emerges as a transformative force, offering a pathway to understand, interpret, and trust AI-driven decisions, and providing transformational leaders with the tools they need to navigate the complexities of modern business with confidence and integrity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Big Opportunities of Big Data</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-next-big-opportunities-of-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-next-big-opportunities-of-big-data/</guid>
      <description>In the era of Big Data, great new opportunities are continually being created for virtually all business functions. Through Big Data, companies can accumulate competitive benefits, which can be conclusive if they also learn to use them on an efficient scale and are able to routinize the extraction of value from data using appropriate techniques.
In this article we examine some of the main impacts and opportunities that Big Data will continue to provide to business organizations in the development of innovative and increasingly competitive strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-code/No-code- Unlocking Software Development Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/low-code-no-code-unlocking-software-development-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/low-code-no-code-unlocking-software-development-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Companies are facing a shortage of software developers around the world. No matter what statistic or report you read, everyone seems to agree on one thing: the number of software developers needed to cover all of the industry&amp;rsquo;s needs is staggering and only increasing.
For example, IDC has forecast a global shortage of four million software developers by 2025, while the US Bureau of Labor Statistics shows that nearly 200,000 developer jobs will be needed each year until the end of the decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Leadership that Business Transformation Demands</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Business transformation is best managed when there are smart leaders who recognize the needs of the organization and are willing to guide it on the right direction. The other side of the coin is that smart leadership is a critical capability that companies urgently need to equip themselves with to address all the transformational changes required to build a new culture based on agile and continuous transformation.
What&amp;rsquo;s more, smart leadership is a critical competency needed to successfully embrace Big data and AI-based advanced technology initiatives across the organization and truly reap the benefits of business transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-successful-business-transformation-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Smart organizations are constantly changing, adapting their structures, resources, and objectives as they evolve to overcome the inertia that impedes change. Building a transformation strategy on top of the dynamic capabilities and ambidexterity of the organization, and through the implementation of multiple simultaneous projects is an effective way to reduce risks and have better cost performance.
This approach when setting the business transformation strategy is different when organizations perceive the need to transform as a result of episodic external events (aka, disruptions) that alter a previous equilibrium situation and that affect the organization&amp;rsquo;s internal structures, forcing them to be replaced by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Business Transformation with Ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/managing-business-transformation-with-ambidexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/managing-business-transformation-with-ambidexterity/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s complex business context, addressing business transformation means that organizations must develop new capabilities to quickly adapt to both predictable and unpredictable environmental changes and create (and capture) new value.
External events such as the emergence of new technologies and new disruptive and innovative business models, the shortening of product life cycles and a more dynamic competitive landscape require new strategic responses.
Transformational leaders often address this challenge by adopting different combinations of information technologies, processes and resources that greatly affect the entire organization and lead to radical changes in its structure, culture, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Capabilities- The Holy Grail of Strategic Change Management</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/dynamic-capabilities-the-holy-grail-of-strategic-change-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/dynamic-capabilities-the-holy-grail-of-strategic-change-management/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s business environment marked by strong competition and continuous pressure for organizations to transform and not stop innovating, an endless number of new difficulties and challenges arise that transformational leaders must manage.
Companies need to constantly adjust their strategies to remain relevant, and having a solid business transformation strategy that is well aligned with the rest of the organization&amp;rsquo;s strategies becomes essential.
In this complicated game, it is crucial that transformational leaders effectively manage the set of capabilities that organizations possess to respond to environmental changes and maintain a high level of performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
