<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Basics on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Basics on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation, Evolutionary or Disruptive?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</guid>
      <description>The idea of &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo; refers to a process of profound and evolutionary change that affects all aspects of an organization, led by digital capabilities and technologies aimed at creating value. The fact that digital transformation is an evolutionary process indicates that the phenomenon of transformation is continuous; that is, it is maintained over time.
Some authors, however, argue that digital transformation involves more radical or disruptive change than simply an evolutionary process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Confused with Digitization, Digitalization and Digital Transformation?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/still-confused-with-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/still-confused-with-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Being clear about the main concepts surrounding that of digitalization is no longer straightforward. The term has been so abused by so many people with so many different intentions that it has ceased to be useful for sharing ideas with each other, and shrouded in tons of dust and without substance.
To make matters worse, the literature on digitalization and related disciplines does not help at all if we seek to clarify things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is and What Is Not Big Data?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/what-is-and-what-is-not-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/what-is-and-what-is-not-big-data/</guid>
      <description>It is not easy to define what Big Data is, or to draw a clear dividing line between what is “big” and “small” data. This difficulty is reflected in the number and variety of conceptualizations that can be found about Big Data in the literature.
Big Data promises exciting new opportunities, including unlocking new insights that can accelerate the creation of new products and services, boost customer relationships, improve operational processes, and even embrace innovative business models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Types of AI Are There and What Are They For?</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-many-types-of-ai-are-there-and-what-are-they-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-many-types-of-ai-are-there-and-what-are-they-for/</guid>
      <description>The term artificial intelligence (AI) was first introduced in the 1950s as a branch of computer science concerned with the automation of intelligent behavior. Since then, AI and its associated techniques have developed rapidly to the point that today not only is there still no fully accepted definition of what AI is, but there are various approaches to it.
Most frequently, AI is associated with the ability of a machine to sense its environment, learn from experience, make decisions based on input and goals, and ultimately perform human-like tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
