<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digitalization on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</title>
    <link>/tags/digitalization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digitalization on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/digitalization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Transformation, Evolutionary or Disruptive?</title>
      <link>/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/digital-transformation-evolutionary-or-disruptive/</guid>
      <description>The idea of &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo; refers to a process of profound and evolutionary change that affects all aspects of an organization, led by digital capabilities and technologies aimed at creating value. The fact that digital transformation is an evolutionary process indicates that the phenomenon of transformation is continuous; that is, it is maintained over time. Some authors, however, argue that digital transformation involves more radical or disruptive change than simply an evolutionary process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Confused with the Differences between Digitization, Digitalization and Digital Transformation?</title>
      <link>/posts/still-confused-with-the-differences-between-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/still-confused-with-the-differences-between-digitization-digitalization-and-digital-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Being clear about the main concepts surrounding that of digitalization is no longer straightforward. The term has been so abused by so many people with so many different intentions that it has ceased to be useful for sharing ideas with each other, and shrouded in tons of dust and without substance.
To make matters worse, the literature on digitalization and related disciplines does not help at all if we seek to clarify things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
