<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformation Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Leadership for Business Transformation</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/new-leadership-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>Business transformation is best managed when there are smart leaders who recognize the needs of the organization and are willing to guide it on the right direction. Smart leadership is a critical capability that companies need in order to address all the transformational changes required to build a data-driven culture in the organization. Furthermore, leadership is a critical competency to embrace Big Data throughout the organization and bring the benefits of data science to fruition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies (II)</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-ii/</guid>
      <description>(&amp;hellip;)
Value offerings Smart technologies provide the ability for companies to create new value offerings from reviewing or expanding their existing portfolio of products and services. These new value offerings are determined by the organization’s ability to collect and analyze data on customers from their interactions with the products and services, as well as by incorporating increasingly innovative elements into them.
A paradigmatic example of the creation of new value offerings through smart technologies is Airbnb, whose business model is based on the ability to collect information from customers and partners and use data insights to better understand how customers travel and what accommodations they prefer when visiting a travel destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a Successful Transformation Strategy with Smart Technologies (I)</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/setting-up-a-seamless-business-transformation-strategy-i/</guid>
      <description>Smart organizations are constantly changing, adapting their structures, resources, and objectives as they evolve to overcome the inertia that impedes change. Building a transformation strategy on top of the dynamic capabilities and ambidexterity of the company through the implementation of multiple simultaneous projects is an effective way to reduce risks and have better cost performance.
This is different from those organizations that perceive the need to transform as a result of episodic external events (or disruptions) that alter a previous equilibrium situation and that affect the internal structures of the organization, which must then be replaced by others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Smart Transformation by Developing Dynamic Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/tackling-smart-transformation-by-developing-dynamic-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/tackling-smart-transformation-by-developing-dynamic-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>In the new era of data and smart technologies, the consumer is king when companies must decide on new technologies and business transformation. In these new times, the tangible resources (including the tangible products) on which the fundamental competitive capabilities of businesses were based are beginning to lose relevance in favor of the intangible assets and services delivered by the organization. Furthermore, the ability of organizations to open up to the outside world and interact with other players in multiple business ecosystems becomes critical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
