<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Governance on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Governance on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Adopt Open Innovation with Agility for Business Transformation</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-to-adopt-open-innovation-with-agility-for-business-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/how-to-adopt-open-innovation-with-agility-for-business-transformation/</guid>
      <description>The complex environment in which most business organizations operate around the world has made the practices that lead to open innovation become an essential tool for any transformational leader who relies on the potential of external ideas, knowledge, and technologies to create value.
Organizations with greater external knowledge and skills are in a better position to make faster decisions and adapt their operating frameworks to changes in the environment and threats from competitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Agile Practices for Transformational Leaders</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/best-agile-practices-for-transformational-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/best-agile-practices-for-transformational-leaders/</guid>
      <description>Transformational leaders committed to moving towards smart, data-driven management should start thinking about how they can improve their organization&amp;rsquo;s agility, which means first having a good understanding of what an Agile framework is about and choosing which practices and methodologies are best suited to expedite the implementation of transformation initiatives.
Not surprisingly, one of the main obstacles to adopting an Agile framework and speeding up business transformation is the often misinformed choice of the tools and techniques that are most valuable to teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Democratization of Smartness with Big Data, Analytics and AI as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-democratization-of-smartness-with-big-data-analytics-and-ai-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-democratization-of-smartness-with-big-data-analytics-and-ai-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The seamless integration of Big Data, Analytics and AI (BDAI) into solutions that meet the changing needs of business is starting to generate great business opportunities and competitive advantages for companies in all industries around the world.
Simultaneously, the rise of the &amp;ldquo;as-a-service&amp;rdquo; trend is gaining momentum thanks to the proliferation of the amount of data available and the exponential increase in computing capabilities. Not to mention that more and more companies have access to IT infrastructure and applications as a service through the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
