<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</title>
    <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Bringing Top-notch Insights to Transformational Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Explainable AI- A Gateway to Transparent Decision-Making</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/explainable-ai-a-gateway-to-transparent-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/explainable-ai-a-gateway-to-transparent-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>In the era of data-driven decision-making, businesses are increasingly turning to Artificial Intelligence (AI) to gain insights, streamline processes, and enhance competitiveness. However, as AI systems become more complex and pervasive, the need for transparency and accountability in their decision-making processes has become paramount.
This is where Explainable AI (XAI) emerges as a transformative force, offering a pathway to understand, interpret, and trust AI-driven decisions, and providing transformational leaders with the tools they need to navigate the complexities of modern business with confidence and integrity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transformative Power of the Connected Autonomous Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-transformative-power-of-the-connected-autonomous-vehicle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-transformative-power-of-the-connected-autonomous-vehicle/</guid>
      <description>Connected and autonomous vehicles (CAVs) have the potential to disrupt industries and consumer behavior, transforming urban spaces, modes of transportation use, and a significant portion mobility-related employment. The arrival of CAVs on the market will generate a new world of business and social opportunities that, however, are not free from challenges and threats.
CAVs are much more than &amp;ldquo;autonomous taxis&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;constructive policy dialogue&amp;rdquo;, they raise concrete questions about how to design the cities in which we will live, where businesses will be located and how consumer experiences will be designed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Big Opportunities of Big Data</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-next-big-opportunities-of-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-next-big-opportunities-of-big-data/</guid>
      <description>In the era of Big Data, great new opportunities are continually being created for virtually all business functions. Through Big Data, companies can accumulate competitive benefits, which can be conclusive if they also learn to use them on an efficient scale and are able to routinize the extraction of value from data using appropriate techniques.
In this article we examine some of the main impacts and opportunities that Big Data will continue to provide to business organizations in the development of innovative and increasingly competitive strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Key Ingredients of a Successful Cybersecurity Strategy</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-3-key-ingredients-of-a-successful-cybersecurity-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-3-key-ingredients-of-a-successful-cybersecurity-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Stories of cyber-attacks have become routine, with cyber-attackers showing increasing levels of sophistication and damage inflicted. The race to discover new ways to exploit weaknesses in the defenses of every company&amp;rsquo;s data and IT systems does not stop, so it is absolutely key that transformational leaders are aware of the magnitude of the challenges they face and understand what is at stake.
Unless transformational leaders are relentless in responding to the threats posed by cyberattacks and put all the resources necessary to mitigate them, cyberattackers will exploit the flaws and weaknesses of the organization&amp;rsquo;s data and IT systems to hijack, distort, or simply interrupt the organization&amp;rsquo;s service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-code/No-code- Unlocking Software Development Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/low-code-no-code-unlocking-software-development-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/low-code-no-code-unlocking-software-development-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Companies are facing a shortage of software developers around the world. No matter what statistic or report you read, everyone seems to agree on one thing: the number of software developers needed to cover all of the industry&amp;rsquo;s needs is staggering and only increasing.
For example, IDC has forecast a global shortage of four million software developers by 2025, while the US Bureau of Labor Statistics shows that nearly 200,000 developer jobs will be needed each year until the end of the decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Democratization of Smartness with Big Data, Analytics and AI as-a-Service</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-democratization-of-smartness-with-big-data-analytics-and-ai-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/the-democratization-of-smartness-with-big-data-analytics-and-ai-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The seamless integration of Big Data, Analytics and AI (BDAI) into solutions that meet the changing needs of business is starting to generate great business opportunities and competitive advantages for companies in all industries around the world.
Simultaneously, the rise of the &amp;ldquo;as-a-service&amp;rdquo; trend is gaining momentum thanks to the proliferation of the amount of data available and the exponential increase in computing capabilities. Not to mention that more and more companies have access to IT infrastructure and applications as a service through the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Systems - Boosting Your Business Smart Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/cognitive-systems-boosting-your-business-smart-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/cognitive-systems-boosting-your-business-smart-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive computing technologies are fundamentally different from all other forms of computing seen so far. They aim to continually learn from the interaction between data (structured and unstructured), context, and people, to improve learning and reasoning capabilities over time.
Similar to how human learning evolves from birth to adulthood, a cognitive system learns and becomes more intelligent over time from the information it gains each time it interacts with its environment and the experience it accumulates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Applications Worth Considering Today</title>
      <link>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://frontiersinbusinesstransformation.com/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-today/</guid>
      <description>The idea of quantum computing emerged years ago from the reflections of a bunch of scientists about what the fundamental limits of computing were. What they assumed was that if technology continued to comply with Moore&amp;rsquo;s Law, that is, if the number of transistors in a microprocessor doubled approximately every two years, then the decreasing size of the circuits within a silicon chip would eventually reach a point where individual elements would not exceed the size of a few atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
