<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technologies on Top-notch knowledge for Transformation Leaders</title>
    <link>/tags/technologies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technologies on Top-notch knowledge for Transformation Leaders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/technologies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Before and After Computing With Cognitive Systems</title>
      <link>/posts/the-road-ahead-for-cognitive-computing-applications-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-road-ahead-for-cognitive-computing-applications-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>The Road Ahead for Cognitive Computing Applications and Challenges Cognitive computing technologies are fundamentally different from all other forms of computing used so far. Cognitive systems continually learn from their interaction with data (structured and unstructured), contexts, and people, and thus improve their learning and reasoning capabilities over time. Similar to how human learning evolves from birth to adulthood, a cognitive system learns and becomes more intelligent over time from the information it gains each time it interacts with its environment and the experience it accumulates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Rule of Smartness with BDAI as-a-Service</title>
      <link>/posts/opportunities-of-bdai-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/opportunities-of-bdai-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The combination of Big Data, analytics, and AI (BDAI) is going to generate great business opportunities and competitive advantages for companies around the world. Through the integration and interoperability of these technologies, companies are going to be able to transform their operations and business model and, in the medium and long term, obtain significant gains in efficiency and productivity.
It can be expected that the inclusion of BDAI in the culture of people will better prepare organizations to open new markets and explore (and exploit) new niches in existing markets, will allow the creation of new value offerings focused on the experiential component and personalization, and, ultimately, will contribute significantly to boosting growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Applications Worth Considering and Challenges</title>
      <link>/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/quantum-computing-applications-worth-considering-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>The idea of quantum computing arose from the reflection made by scientists about the fundamental limits of computing. What they surmised is that if technology continued to comply with Moore’s Law (which states that the number of transistors in a microprocessor doubles approximately every 2 years), then the shrinking size of the circuits within a silicon chip would eventually reach a point where individual elements would not exceed the size of a few atoms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
